让我们将彩色图像加载到我们的工作区中。
Let’s load a color image into our workspace.
我们将它放入名为im的变量中，并调用我要使用的图像
We’ll put it into the variable called im, and the image that I’m going to use is called
flowers8，它是一个png格式文件。
flowers8 and it’s a png format file.
所以这是随工具箱分发的文件之一。
So this is one of the files that’s distributed with the toolbox.
我们已将其加载到工作区中。
We have loaded it into the workspace.
现在再一次，这是一个无符号的8位整数图像。
Now once again this is an unsigned 8-bit integer image.
我们可以看到图像属于类uint8。
We can see that the image belongs to the class uint8.
与我们之前看到的相比，这张图片的尺寸很有趣。
The dimensions of this image are interesting compared to what we’ve seen before.
我们看到这个有426行，640列和一个带有值的额外维度
We see that this one has got 426 rows, 640 columns and an extra dimension with a value
3。
of 3.
我们将第二维称为平面，并且很快就会变得清晰。
We refer to the second dimension as the plane, and that will become clear shortly.
我们要做的第一件事是显示图像，我们看到一张图片包含
First thing we’re going to do is to display the image and we see a picture containing
一些彩色的花朵。
a number of colored flowers.
现在，如果我点击一些像素值-我将点击这里的红色花-我们
Now if I click on some pixel values—I’m going to click here on this red flower—we
看到它有一个有三个组件的像素值。
see that it has got a pixel value which has three components.
像素值实际上是一个矢量，这些数字表示红色的数量，
The pixel value is actually a vector, and those numbers indicate the amount of red,
绿色量，蓝色量。
the amount of green, the amount of blue.
所以我刚刚点了一朵红色的花，我们看到红色的数量是176，而且这个
So I’ve just clicked on a red flower and we see that the red amount is 176, and this
非常重要。
is quite significant.
请记住，8位无符号整数从最小值开始
Remember, 8-bit unsigned integers go from a minimum
值0到最大值255，所以这个像素中有很多红色。
value of 0 to a maximum value of 255, so this pixel has got quite a lot of red in it.
它几乎没有绿色，而且几乎没有蓝色。
It’s got almost no green, and it’s got almost no blue.
让我们转向一朵粉红色的花。
Let’s move over to a pink flower.
这有点接近白色，我们看到这个像素有很大的数量
This is a bit closer to white, and we see that this pixel has got a significant amount
红色，相当数量的绿色，和相当数量的蓝色。
of red, and a fair amount of green, and a fair amount of blue.
我们来看看这片绿叶，我们看到绿色值是
Let’s go and have a look on a green leaf here, and we see that the green value is the
最大的一个，但那里也有一些红色和蓝色，但以绿色为主。
biggest one, but there is also an amount of red and blue there, but dominated by green.
有一些小小的蓝色花朵，所以我要放大这部分
There are some tiny little blue flowers so I’m going to zoom in on this part of the
图像，然后点击其中一个蓝色的花朵，正如我们所料，蓝色值占主导地位
image, and click on one of those blue flowers, and as we would expect, the blue value dominates
这里。
here.
我们来看看其中一个图像平面。
Let’s have a look at one of these image planes.
我要显示图像。
I am going to display the image.
我将显示所有行和所有列，但仅显示属于平面的那些像素
I’m going to display all rows and all columns, but only those pixels that belong to plane
1号。
number 1.
我们终于得到它了。
And there we have it.
现在这是灰度图像。
This is now a grey scale image.
颜色已全部消失，这是红色平面，第一个平面。
The color has all gone and this is the red plane, the first plane.
如果我看一下这里的值，我们会发现它们在红色的地方非常明亮
And if I look at the values here we see that they are quite bright where there was red
在图像中，在图像中没有红色的情况下，它们非常暗。
in the image, and they’re very dark where there was no red in the image.
因此绿色的叶子会变黑，蓝色的花朵会变暗。
So it will be dark in the green leaves, it will be dark on the blue flowers.
我们可以看看绿色平面，那是2号飞机。
We can look at the green plane, that’s plane number 2.
我们可以看到这看起来很不一样。
We can see that this looks quite different.
红色的花很暗-这是因为它们没有任何绿色-而是
The red flowers are quite dark—that’s because they don’t have any green in them—whereas
叶子看起来比以前更亮一些，粉红色的白色
the leaves are looking a little bit brighter than they were before, and the pinky white
鲜花也看起来相当明亮，因为白色的花朵有混合物
flowers are also looking reasonably bright because the white flowers have got a mixture
红色和绿色和蓝色。
of red and green and blue.
最后，我们可以看看蓝色平面，那是第三个平面。
Finally, we can look at the blue plane, that’s the third plane.
在这里，我们看到底部的小蓝花现在看起来非常明亮。
And here we see that the little blue flowers around the bottom are now looking quite bright.
正如我前面提到的那样，白色的花朵，我前面提到的粉红色的白色花朵，也在寻找
The white flowers as I mentioned, pinky white flowers as I mentioned before, are also looking
相当明亮，因为它们含有相当数量的蓝色。
reasonably bright because they contain a fair amount of blue.
绿叶也看起来很暗，因为没有太多的蓝色被反射
The green leaves are also looking quite dark because there’s not much blue being reflected
从那些叶子。
from those leaves.
我们可以将彩色图像视为包含三个平面。
We can consider a color image then as comprising three planes.
我们将它们称为红色，绿色和蓝色平面。
We refer to those as the red, green and blue planes.
我们可以认为每个平面都是灰度图像，其中像素值对应于
Each plane we can consider to be a grey scale image, where the pixel value corresponds to
该特定像素位置处的原色数量。
the amount of that primary color at that particular pixel location.
因此，如果我们在这里看到这些白色的花朵，我们会看到它们在红色和绿色中是明亮的
So if we look at these white flowers here, we see that they are bright in the red, green
和蓝色图像。
and blue images.
这意味着那些白色的花朵含有大量的红色，还有很多绿色和许多
That means that those white flowers contain a lot of red, and a lot of green and a lot
蓝色
of blue.
相比之下，红色图像中的红色花朵非常明亮，但它们非常非常
By contrast, the red flowers are quite bright in the red image, but they’re very, very
绿色和蓝色图像中的黑暗。
dark in the green and blue images.
所以红色的花朵包含许多红色，正如你所料，绿色不是很多
So the red flowers comprise a lot of red color, as you would expect, not much green and not
很蓝。
much blue.
我们可以看到黄色的花朵在红色和绿色的图像中是明亮的;就是他们
We can see that the yellow flowers are bright in the red and green images; that is, they
反射红光和绿光，但它们不反射蓝光。
reflect red light and green light, but they do not reflect blue light.
如果我们将彩色图像视为一组平面，红色绿色和蓝色，请想象它们
If we consider our color image as a stack of planes, red green and blue, imagine them
一个堆叠在另一个之上。
stacked up one above the other.
因此，当谈到描述彩色图像中的像素时，我们将描述像素
So when it comes to describe a pixel in a color image now, we describe the pixel at
坐标u，v，这就是我们以前做过的事情;你是水平坐标，
the coordinate u,v and this is what we’ve done previously; u is the horizontal coordinate,
v是垂直坐标。
v is the vertical coordinate.
现在我们要做的是深入了解这一堆图像。
And now what we’re going to do is drill down through this stack of images.
所以这是红色值，然后我们找到绿色值，然后我们找到蓝色值。
So this is the red value, then we find the green value, and then we find the blue value.
所以在坐标u，v处，像素值实际上由三个数字组成。
So at the coordinate u,v the pixel value is actually comprised of three numbers.
它是一个三元素矢量：包含红色，绿色和蓝色成分。
It is a three-element vector: contains a red, green and blue component.
我们之前已经看过我们在MATLAB中索引矩阵的方式，在MATLAB中我们
We’ve previously looked at the way we index into a matrix in MATLAB, and in MATLAB we
表示具有两个坐标的矩阵。
represent a matrix with two coordinates.
第一个坐标是行号，第二个坐标是列号。
The first coordinate is the row number, and the second coordinate is the column number.
在彩色图像中，就MATLAB而言，它是一个三维矩阵，并且
In a color image it’s a three-dimensional matrix as far as MATLAB is concerned, and
我们再次使用一堆飞机的类比。
again we use this analogy of a stack of planes.
所以，第一个索引是行号，第二个索引是列号和
So again, the first index is the row number, the second index is the column number and
第三个指标就是我们所说的飞机号码。
the third index is what we call the plane number.
它是我们所指的堆栈中的哪个工作表。
It’s which sheet in the stack that we are referring to.
正如我在之前的一次演讲中提到的那样谨慎：我们在谈论的时候
And there’s a caution as I’ve mentioned in an earlier lecture: when we are talking
关于在MATLAB中索引图像，我们使用行后跟列。
about indexing into an image in MATLAB, we use the row followed by the column.
当我们参考图像时，我们通常是指水平坐标，然后是垂直坐标
When we refer to an image we generally refer to the horizontal coordinate, then the vertical
坐标，它们被转置;他们被交换了。
coordinate, and they are transposed; they are swapped.
所以要小心。
So be careful with that.
我们可以这样编程;也就是说，从命令行。
We can do this programmatically; that is, from the command line.
所以我们有了自己的形象。
So we have our image.
让我们看看坐标100,100处像素的值，我们想看一下
Let’s look at the value of the pixel at coordinate 100,100, and we want to look at
所有的飞机。
all of the planes.
我们从MATLAB得到了这个相当奇怪的结果。
We get this rather strange result from MATLAB.
正如我们所料，它已经使用了三个数字：红色，绿色和蓝色，
It has given use three numbers, as we would expect: the amount of red, green and blue,
但是形式相当不方便。
but in a rather inconvenient form.
当我们这样做时，我们实际上必须使用MATLAB运算符，以删除两个
We actually have to use the MATLAB operator squeeze when we do this, to remove two of
MATLAB所指的单身尺寸。
what MATLAB refers to as singleton dimensions.
因此，如果我们现在这样做，我们就有了这个特定像素的矢量值。
So if we do that now we have a vector value for this particular pixel.